Department of Chemistry Records UA151
Tufts Archival Research Center
Department of Chemistry Records
1909 -- 2010
Tufts Archival Research Center
School of Arts and Sciences
Department of Chemistry
UA151
14.4 Linear Feet 11 boxes
1 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series: Undergraduate theses; Graduate theses; Photographs and slides; and Publications.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains graduate brochures, undergraduate and graduate theses, photographs, and slides from the Chemistry Department.
Biographical / Historical
Professor Arthur Michael established the Department of Chemistry in 1882. In 1894, students were allowed for the first time to choose Chemistry as their academic major. Chemistry became one of twelve academic majors undergraduate students could choose as the focus of their studies.
The Department of Chemistry offers both its undergraduate and graduate students the resources and opportunities of a top-ranked research university while providing the individual attention, mentoring, and training of a smaller institution. Members of the Department provide guidance and advice to both undergraduates and graduates and work closely with them to ensure academic success.
Highly motivated undergraduates are encouraged to participate in a wide range of research projects under the leadership of faculty members. Research projects are varied in focus and deal with issues such as climate change, disease mitigation, and alternative energy.
The Department of Chemistry offers graduate programs at both the M.S. and the Ph.D. level in the following sub disciplines of Chemistry: organic, inorganic, physical, and analytical. The Department of Chemistry also offers joint graduate programs with the Tufts University Biotechnology Center. These joint graduate programs offer M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Chemistry/Biotechnology for those students who are interested in applying their chemical training to emerging areas of biotechnology.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work
- Undergraduate Theses, 1910 -- 1967; UA151.001; 10.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the Department of Chemistry Undergraduate theses.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged numerically by volume.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - A further investigation of some derivatives of orthosuphobenzoic acid, 1910; UA151.001.001.00001; Fuller, G. P. (Box 1)
    Dept. of Chemistry
  - Crucible experiments with a Mexican silver ore, 1910; UA151.001.001.00002; Baker, Crosby F. (Box 1)
  - Total solids in water analysis, 1911; UA151.001.001.00003; Willis, R. L. (Box 1)
  - Utilization of the residue from acetylene gas manufacture, 1911; UA151.001.001.00004; Gurney, Elmer A. (Box 1)
  - Cyanide tests of a Mexican ore, 1911; UA151.001.001.00005; Daly, C. T. (Box 1)
  - A chemical analysis and comparison of the Somerville slate or argillite, and the Medford glacial brick clay, 1912; UA151.001.001.00006; Carter, Louis Hayward (Box 1)
  - The method for the determination of potassium as the di-potassium-sodium-cobalti-nitrite, K2NaCo (NO2)6, 1912; UA151.001.001.00007; Savage, Percy G. (Box 1)
  - A sanitary examination of the water of the Medford Clay Pits, near Tufts College, during the fall, winter and spring of 1911-12, 1912; UA151.001.001.00009; Bogue, Robert H. (Box 1)
  - Castor oil as a possible soap stock, 1913; UA151.001.001.00010; Monge, L. E. (Box 1)
  - The recovery of tannin from spent sumach, 1913; UA151.001.001.00011; Carter, Herbert Melville (Box 1)
  - Adaptability of silver ore #1 to the cyanide process, 1913; UA151.001.001.00012; Harrington, Rufus Frost (Box 1)
  - Determination of formaldehyde and formic acid in the presence of each other and disappearance of sulphurous acid upon long standing, 1913; UA151.001.001.00013; Rindge, Wellington (Box 1)
  - Waste sugar house molasses as a possible source of ethyl alcohol, 1913; UA151.001.001.00014a; Clavell, Antonia Cepero (Box 1)
  - Determination of lead as sulphate in presence of tin and antimony, 1914; UA151.001.001.00014b; Whittemore, Francis D. (Box 1)
  - A comparative analysis of road oils, 1914; UA151.001.001.00015; Cosgrove, Frederick S. (Box 1)
  - Cyanide experiments with a cyanide ore, 1914; UA151.001.001.00016; Chandler, Warren R. (Box 1)
  - Tensile strength of white metal as affected by varying percentages of tin and antimony, 1914; UA151.001.001.00017; Greenbaum, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Effect on tensile strength of samples of white metal where lead increases and tin decreases, 1914; UA151.001.001.00018; Tower, Henry E. (Box 1)
  - Comparative analysis of ten standard cements with tensile strength, 1914; UA151.001.001.00019; Turner, Nelson W. (Box 1)
  - The volumetric determination of tin, using iron and steel as the reducing agent, 1914; UA151.001.001.00020; Savage, Harold R. (Box 1)
  - A set of experiments to be used in connection with Chemistry-10, 1914; UA151.001.001.00021; Nelligan, H. P. (Box 1)
  - Water-proofing of shoe-sole felt, 1915; UA151.001.001.00022; Lindstol, Carl F. (Box 1)
  - Determination of arsenic in wall paper, 1915; UA151.001.001.00023; Magee, Joseph Vincent (Box 1)
  - A method for the accurate determination of the mineral fillers of a rubber compound, 1915; UA151.001.001.00024; Brooks, William Gooch (Box 1)
  - Glycerin manufacture and determination of impurities, 1915; UA151.001.001.00025; McPherson, Edmund Stow (Box 1)
  - Solubility of mixtures of KNO3 - NaNO3 - NaCl at 20 degrees C, 1915; UA151.001.001.00026; Whitney, Donald H. (Box 1)
  - Analysis of deep mine waters, 1915; UA151.001.001.00027; Fessenden, Margaret Tebbetts (Box 1)
  - An investigation of the preparation of ethylene from sulphuric acid and alcohol, 1915; UA151.001.001.00028; Chapman, W. A. (Box 1)
  - The chemical examination of soil with reference to geological formation and crop raising, 1915; UA151.001.001.00029; Phillips, Arthur Welch; Phillips, Ralph Oliver (Box 1)
  - The chemical analysis and the mineralogical examination of the Malden felsite to determine it's value as road material, 1915; UA151.001.001.00030; Lybeck, Robert Ferdinand (Box 1)
  - A study of 2-4-diphenyl-3-thio semicarbazide, 1-4-diphenyl-5-thiolurazole, and the methyl and methyl thiol esters, 1915; UA151.001.001.00031; Barnes, Maxwell F. (Box 1)
  - Thesis on cement, 1915; UA151.001.001.00032; Angell, George (Box 1)
  - An investigation of refiner's molasses, 1915; UA151.001.001.00033; Morison, Frederick S. (Box 1)
  - The fermentation of cider, 1915; UA151.001.001.00034; Sullivan, Harry M. (Box 1)
  - The composition and probable origin of the water of the Neopolitan Ice Cream Company, 1915; UA151.001.001.00035; Robbins, Roger S. (Box 1)
  - The removal of iron from the water supply of the City of Waltham, Massachusetts, 1916; UA151.001.001.00036; Flagg, Frederick P. (Box 1)
  - A study of xylose, 1916; UA151.001.001.00037; Spencer, Clayton Cree (Box 1)
  - A study of fluorescein and the preparation of phloxine its tetrabrom-dichlor-derrivative, 1916; UA151.001.001.00038; Nixon, Alexander C. Jr. (Box 1)
  - The fibres of rag papers, rag half-stocks and of wood pulps measured and compared, 1916; UA151.001.001.00039; Loomis, Samuel (Box 1)
  - Investigation of a proposed method for the determination of mineral substance in rubber compounds, 1916; UA151.001.001.00040; Stafford, Henry Alexander (Box 1)
  - Determination of nicotine in manufactured tobaccos, 1916; UA151.001.001.00041; Smith, John Blackmer (Box 1)
  - The synthesis of magenta, spirit blue, water soluble blue and intermediate products, 1916; UA151.001.001.00042; Shapiro, Frank S. (Box 1)
  - Dry distillation of lead acetate in the presence of iron sulphide and preparation of aspirin, 1916; UA151.001.001.00043; Pollock, Israel (Box 1)
  - The effect of conditions on the absolute migration velocity of the hydrogen ion, and a determination of the absolute migration velocity of the copper ion, 1916; UA151.001.001.00044; Bixby, Madeleine (Box 1)
  - Study of the hydrolysis of methyl acetate by acids, 1916; UA151.001.001.00045; Towne, Lester Newton (Box 1)
  - Motor lubricating oils, 1916; UA151.001.001.00046; Morrison, Arthur Winchester (Box 1)
  - The cyanide process, 1916; UA151.001.001.00047; Murphy, Leo Thomas (Box 1)
  - The chemical analysis of a soil area from the Allen farm with reference to its conformity in chemical constituents and value as a crop-producing area, 1916; UA151.001.001.00048; Allen, Windom A. (Box 1)
  - A study of the quantitative determination of fructose by means of the colored compound with resorcinol and hydrocholic acid, 1916; UA151.001.001.00049; Donnellan, Arthur V. (Box 1)
  - A study of arabinose and its quantitative determination, 1916; UA151.001.001.00050; Reed, Everett Lenox (Box 1)
  - An investigation of electrolytic reduction of indigo and a derivative, 1916; UA151.001.001.00051; Staples, Carl W. (Box 1)
  - The determination of arsenic in cloth, 1916; UA151.001.001.00052; Tennis, Max (Box 1)
  - Study of a possible hydrometallurgical method for the extraction of copper from South Strafford ore, 1916; UA151.001.001.00053; Town, Cecil Benton (Box 1)
  - Research on the literature of nitrotoluols and toluidines and a method for the separation of nitrotoluols and for the proparation of para- and ortho-toluidine, 1917; UA151.001.001.00054; Minevitch, Joseph R. (Box 1)
  - The analysis and testing of gelatine and gelatine solutions, 1917; UA151.001.001.00055; Sefton, Archibald K. (Box 1)
  - Electrolytic cyaniding process for the extraction of silver, 1917; UA151.001.002.00056; Jones, H. W. (Box 2)
  - Galvanizing and recovery of its waste products, 1917; UA151.001.002.00057; Williams, Harold J. (Box 2)
  - The use of alundum crucibles in gravimetric analysis, 1917; UA151.001.002.00058; Mohor, Albert J. (Box 2)
  - A study of the relative accuracy of the methods employing copper solutions in the determination of sugars, 1917; UA151.001.002.00059; Rourke, John J. (Box 2)
  - A quick fermented dough, 1917; UA151.001.002.00060; Bratt, Albert Verner (Box 2)
  - A research on rubber insulating materials, 1917; UA151.001.002.00061; Collins, George (Box 2)
  - A chemical study of East Lexington peat, 1917; UA151.001.002.00062; Claff, Elmer Louis (Box 2)
  - Recovery of cyanides from spent oxide of gas works, 1917; UA151.001.002.00063; Hurley, Harold Francis (Box 2)
  - The analysis of Chuguicamata copper ore and determination of the minerals present, 1917; UA151.001.002.00064; Scamman, Willliam M. (Box 2)
  - Air furnace experiments on the elimination of impurities in cast iron, 1918; UA151.001.002.00065; Finnell, Norman Croft (Box 2)
  - The variation of market cabbage in nutritive value, 1918; UA151.001.002.00066; Perkins, Madeline Abby (Box 2)
  - The influence of some common gangue minerals on the nature and situation of secondary copper sulphide ores, 1918; UA151.001.002.00067; Mendum, W. Clark (Box 2)
  - The smelting of cement copper, 1919; UA151.001.002.00068; Piper, Arthur M. (Box 2)
  - The preparation and properties of phenyl-nitro-methane, 1920; UA151.001.002.00069; Anderson, Paul J. (Box 2)
  - Action of phenyl isocyanate and phenyl isothiocyanate on the ethyl ester of acetone dicarbonic acid, 1920; UA151.001.002.00070; Cahoon, Sumner R. (Box 2)
  - Evolution method for determining sulphur in organic compounds, 1920; UA151.001.002.00071; Chapman, S. (Box 2)
  - An attempt to find a satisfactory method for the determination of moisture in crude calcium acetate, 1920; UA151.001.002.00072; Given, Minott Denham (Box 2)
  - The rancidity of castor oil, 1920; UA151.001.002.00073; Hall, Webster (Box 2)
  - The purification of crude cuban sugar cane wax, 1920; UA151.001.002.00074; Leach, Edgar Percy (Box 2)
  - Preparation of an unsaturated hydrocarbon containing a triple bond, 1920; UA151.001.002.00075; Lipkin, George (Box 2)
  - The preparation of aliphatic nitriles, 1920; UA151.001.002.00076; Mitchell, I. (Box 2)
  - Preparation and reactions of diphenic acid, 1920; UA151.001.002.00077; Mullin, Charles King (Box 2)
  - Attempts upon the labratory preparation of Diamino "H" acid, 1920; UA151.001.002.00078; Olim, Jacob J. (Box 2)
  - The investigation of the quality and food value of milk sold by prominent suburban dealers 1919-1920, UA151.001.002.00079; Pigott, Madeleine G. (Box 2)
  - Chromium Chromate, 1920; UA151.001.002.00080; Prescott, Daniel Alfred (Box 2)
  - The chemical analysis and the mineralogical examination of the rock known as "cumberlandite" to determine the presence of the rarer elements, 1920; UA151.001.002.00081; Rogers, Harold Arthur (Box 2)
  - The recovery of wool from rags by separation from silk and wool, 1920; UA151.001.002.00082; Stone, Donald Pitman (Box 2)
  - Preparation of chlorine-free benzoic acid from toluene, 1921; UA151.001.002.00083; Arratto, Frederic J. (Box 2)
  - Preparation and properties of novocaine, 1921; UA151.001.002.00084; Atkinson, Stewart B. (Box 2)
  - The purification and melting point determination of p-Toluidine, 1921; UA151.001.002.00085; Bishop, Leslie S. (Box 2)
  - The addition of the 1-3 diketones to the isothiocyanates, 1921; UA151.001.002.00086; Bixby, Harriet (Box 2)
  - The preparation and properties of Orange II, 1921; UA151.001.002.00087; Blair, Robert (Box 2)
  - The adaptability of phenanthrene to industry, 1921; UA151.001.002.00088; Brown, Lyman R. (Box 2)
  - Synthesis of fluorene, 1921; UA151.001.002.00089; Chen, Hsi-Ching (Box 2)
  - The preparation and properties of monobenzoylphenanthrene, 1921; UA151.001.002.00090; Cohen, Harry (Box 2)
  - Sulphur or sulphide colors and sulphur red, 1921; UA151.001.002.00091; Collieson, John A. (Box 2)
  - The probable origin of Lynn clays as indicated by a chemical analysis, 1921; UA151.001.002.00092; Collins, Arthur Albert (Box 2)
  - The electrolytic oxidation of manganates to permanganates in the manufacture of potassium permanganate, 1921; UA151.001.002.00093; Cushing, Lovell M. (Box 2)
  - Phenylation of rosaniline, 1921; UA151.001.002.00094; Dee, William J. (Box 2)
  - The recovery of glycerine from scrap printers rolls and examination of gasoline sold in and about Boston, 1921; UA151.001.002.00095; Durkee, Robert Brown (Box 2)
  - A quick method for determining acidity of chrome tanned leather, 1921; UA151.001.002.00096; Freedberg, Harry (Box 2)
  - Preparation and properties of chloral hydrate and its derivatives, 1921; UA151.001.002.00097; Garson, Morton S. (Box 2)
  - A study of oil shales, 1921; UA151.001.002.00098; Gould, Douglas (Box 2)
  - The preparation and purification of acetyl acetone, 1921; UA151.001.002.00099; Herculson, John A. (Box 2)
  - Mate: The examination of the South American herb (Yerba Mate), for its food value and drug content and the consideration of its possibilities as an American (United States) soda fountain drink or a tonic for the stimulation of digestive organs, 1921; UA151.001.002.00100; Parsons, Edward C. (Box 2)
  - A study of a Connecticut soil to determine necessary fertilizer, 1921; UA151.001.002.00101; Peterson, Austin G. (Box 2)
  - The oxidation of phenol, 1921; UA151.001.002.00103; Poole, Arthur E. (Box 2)
  - Determination of molecular weights, 1921; UA151.001.002.00104; Schochet, Abraham I. (Box 2)
  - Investigation of the change in color of the dialkylamidoazobenzene compounds, 1921; UA151.001.002.00105; Siegel, S. A. (Box 2)
  - A commercial catalyzer for the hydrogenation of unsaturated oils, 1921; UA151.001.002.00106; Snyder, Benjamin (Box 2)
  - Mixed emulsified mineral and fatty oils as wool lubricants, 1921; UA151.001.002.00107; Taylor, Gavin A. (Box 2)
  - The preparation of xylose from corncobs, 1921; UA151.001.002.00108; Welansky, James (Box 2)
  - Synthesis of chlorine-free benzoic acid from toluene, 1921; UA151.001.002.00109; Wendelstein, Louis A. (Box 2)
  - Water-proofing and damp-proofing matches, 1921; UA151.001.002.00110; Yung, Chi-Chao (Box 2)
  - The action of aromatic amines on dibrombenzalmalonicester, 1922; UA151.001.002.00111; Armstrong, James H. (Box 2)
  - Relative merits of lactic acid, acetic acid and bran for removing Na2S from hides, 1922; UA151.001.002.00112; Beattie, Elizabeth R. (Box 2)
  - The fertilizing value of East Lexington peat, 1922; UA151.001.002.00113; Carodemos, Peter P. (Box 2)
  - Purification of tin ore by roasting, 1922; UA151.001.002.00114; Cassidy, Philip E. (Box 2)
  - The preparation of stilbene from beta trithibenzaldehyde plus copper, zinc, or lead, 1922; UA151.001.003.00115; Clare, Irwin Charles (Box 3)
  - The quantitative determination of boric acid, 1922; UA151.001.003.00116; Cobb, Rosalie M. (Box 3)
  - A study of the water of the Upper Mystic Lake through the months of October 1921 - February 1922 inclusive, UA151.001.003.00117; Cook, F. Raymond (Box 3)
  - Concentration by flotation of a heavy copper sulphide ore, 1922; UA151.001.003.00118; Foley, H. Mahlon (Box 3)
  - Some reactions of piperonylidene acetophenone, 1922; UA151.001.003.00119; Friis, B. S. T. (Box 3)
  - The addition of aromatic amines to bromo nitro anisylidene, 1922; UA151.001.003.00120; Gordon, Samuel M. (Box 3)
  - A study of some methods for the preparation of stilbene, 1922; UA151.001.003.00121; Haley, Leon T. (Box 3)
  - A study of chloridizing roasts on a copper ore, 1922; UA151.001.003.00122; Heard, Joseph R. (Box 3)
  - A possible commercial treatment for a galena silver ore procured from a mine in Newbury, Massachusetts, 1922; UA151.001.003.00123; Hopkins, C. A. (Box 3)
  - A study of the bromine addition products of benzalacetone, 1922; UA151.001.003.00124; Kalber, Wilfrid A. (Box 3)
  - Investigation of methods of preparation of the C:C di-alkyl derivatives of barbituric acid, 1922; UA151.001.003.00125; Kirby, Francis H. (Box 3)
  - Determination of true free sulphur in rubber compound, 1922; UA151.001.003.00126; Marple, Howard A. (Box 3)
  - Magee Furnace Company and Walker-Pratt Furnace Company, 1922; UA151.001.003.00127; Moore, William H. (Box 3)
  - An investigation to determine percentages of methyl and ethyl alcohols by differential oxidation, 1922; UA151.001.003.00128; Motschman, Frederick William (Box 3)
  - Detection and determination of arsenic in iron pyrites, 1922; UA151.001.003.00129; Mullin, Walter J. (Box 3)
  - The rate of reaction of dichlormine-t with carbon tetrachloride and alcohol as solvents, 1922; UA151.001.003.00130; Peakes, Ernest C. (Box 3)
  - A study of some choline derivatives, 1922; UA151.001.003.00131; Pesce, Guy C. (Box 3)
  - The action of nitric acid on castor oil, 1922; UA151.001.003.00132; Pickett, George A. Jr. (Box 3)
  - Detection of cotton-seed oil in oleomargarine, 1922; UA151.001.003.00133; Rourke, M. Dorothy (Box 3)
  - A study of the velocity of reaction of dichloramine-t with glacial acetic acid, 1922; UA151.001.003.00134; Schwartz, Earl S. (Box 3)
  - The addition of aromatic amines to A-B, unsaturated nitro compounds, 1922; UA151.001.003.00135; Stone, Michael (Box 3)
  - The effect of certain organic radicals on the color of simple azo dyes, 1922; UA151.001.003.00136; Warnock, Philip B. (Box 3)
  - The chemical condition of copper in some igneous rocks, 1923; UA151.001.003.00137; Coleman, George (Box 3)
  - The preparation of butyl ether, 1923; UA151.001.003.00138; Djerf, Frederick J. (Box 3)
  - The determination of the distribution of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) between water and ether (C2H5)2O, 1923; UA151.001.003.00139; Frolio, Samuel Francis (Box 3)
  - Organic rubber accelerators, 1923; UA151.001.003.00140; Greenbaum, R. D. (Box 3)
  - A study of the chlorine addition products of benzalacetone, 1923; UA151.001.003.00141; Gustafson, Carroll B. (Box 3)
  - An investigation of certain Nahant rocks, 1923; UA151.001.003.00142; Perry, Elwyn L. (Box 3)
  - On the addition of hypochlorous acid to terpen-8-ol, 1923; UA151.001.003.00143; Rasch, Royal H. (Box 3)
  - Condensation of furfuraldehyde and a compound containing active hydrogen, 1923; UA151.001.003.00144; Sindle, Joseph J. (Box 3)
  - A quantitative study of thiocarbanilide, 1923; UA151.001.003.00145; Terrill, Arthur G. (Box 3)
  - Determination of tin in enamel, 1923; UA151.001.003.00146; Kroog, A. B. (Box 3)
  - Study of the copper bearing shale of the Nonesuch Formation of the Keweenawan series Lake Superior Region, 1923; UA151.001.003.00147; Pickard, Maurice H. (Box 3)
  - A nickel ore from Dracut, Massachusetts: It's geology and chemistry, 1923; UA151.001.003.00148; Rounds, H. E. (Box 3)
  - The Dracut nickel ore, 1923; UA151.001.003.00149; Wakeman, Everett Bradley (Box 3)
  - The preparation of phenyl mustard oils of selenium and tellurium, 1924; UA151.001.003.00150; Atkins, Cyril F. (Box 3)
  - The determination of antimony by the permanganate process, 1924; UA151.001.003.00151; Bixby, Emily May (Box 3)
  - The insoluble azo dyes and their properties, 1924; UA151.001.003.00152; Blood, Roger M. (Box 3)
  - The metallurgical treatment of a silver-zinc ore, 1924; UA151.001.003.00153; Kaattari, Waino Arthur (Box 3)
  - Determination of sulphur in cast iron, 1924; UA151.001.003.00154; Leavitt, Paul L. (Box 3)
  - Preparation of Clark & Weston standard cells, 1924; UA151.001.003.00155; Lewis, Henry Stockton Jr. (Box 3)
  - Oxidation of Na4Fe(CN)6 to Na3Fe(CN)6, 1924; UA151.001.003.00156; Pevere, E. F. (Box 3)
  - The depression of the freezing point of ethylene dibromide by the addition of some organic substances, 1924; UA151.001.003.00157; Reed, Halbert W. (Box 3)
  - An investigation of the viscosity of methyl acetate, 1924; UA151.001.003.00158; Sabine, David B. (Box 3)
  - A preliminary report on the effect, if any, of solid mediums such as sand or concentrates, on the rate of diffusion of salts in solution, 1924; UA151.001.003.00159; Spooner, Norman C. (Box 3)
  - The determination of true end point in the titration of water soluble super phosphates, 1923; UA151.001.003.00160; Welsford, William Frederick (Box 3)
  - Analyses of whiting and fertilizer, 1924; UA151.001.003.00161; Wood, Robert (Box 3)
  - Effect of manganese dioxide upon the properties of red rubber during aging, 1925; UA151.001.003.00162; Ballard, J. T. (Box 3)
  - Hygroscopic power of NaCl, 1925; UA151.001.003.00163; Evans, C. E. (Box 3)
  - The effects of certain metals in the determination of tin, 1925; UA151.001.003.00164; Halpersohn, May B. (Box 3)
  - The separation of water from water gas tar emulsion, 1925; UA151.001.003.00165; Kosak, Nathaniel (Box 3)
  - An investigation on the neutralizing strength of mone-calcium phosphate, 1925; UA151.001.003.00166; Crent, Elsa (Box 3)
  - Effect of sodium chloride upon solutions of phenol and water, 1925; UA151.001.003.00167; Ward, Ruth (Box 3)
  - Preparation of a thermocouple for labratory use, 1925; UA151.001.003.00168; Weiner, Louis (Box 3)
  - Intermediate report on the effect of solid mediums such as sand or ore concentrates, on the rate of diffusion of salts in solutions, 1925; UA151.001.003.00169; Wyman, Carl E. (Box 3)
  - The solubility of salt solutions in furfural, 1925; UA151.001.003.00170; Yanovitz, Benjamin (Box 3)
  - Molecular weights by the boiling point method, 1926; UA151.001.003.00171; Atwood, Katherine G. (Box 3)
  - An attempt to prepare a new derivative of holocaine, 1926; UA151.001.004.00172; Cibley, Nathan Lawrence (Box 4)
  - The viscosities of three organic substances in aqueous solution and of urea and urethane in benzene, 1926; UA151.001.004.00173; Covil, Donald F. (Box 4)
  - Report on diffusion of sodium chloride in liquid and suspended solid mediums, 1926; UA151.001.004.00174; Nichols, R. L. (Box 4)